Estelle Ishigo papers, 1941-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Ishigo papers., 1941-1957.; 8.5 linear ft.
  - Biographical Materials and Internment Camp Correspondence., .5 linear ft.
    - Letters and postcards Estelle Ishigo received from her Caucasian friends in the Pomona Assembly Center and the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., 1942-1945.; (73 items) (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Wyoming., Date Created: September 10, 1942.; Item no. 27; (1 folded sheet (4 p.); 22 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Lois commiserates with Estelle over her unhappiness at being at Heart Mountain.
      - Postcard, Los Angeles, Calif., to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Wyoming., Date Created: September 22, 1942.; Item no. 28; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: October 7, 1942.; Item no. 29; (1 folded sheet (4 p.); 22 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: October 29, 1942.; Item no. 30; (1 folded sheet (4 p.); 22 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: November 1942.; Item no. 31; (2 p.; 7 x 13.5 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        A brief letter which presumably accompanied copies of sheet music for Estelle.
      - Postcard, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: November 6, 1942.; Item no. 32; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Postcard, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: December 3, 1942.; Item no. 33; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif., to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: December 17, 1942.; Item no. 34; (4 p.; 17 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Cody Wyoming., Date Created: January 8, 1943.; Item no. 35; (1 folded sheet (4 p.); 22 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: February 12, 1943.; Item no. 36; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Letter from a close friend of Estelle's containing updates on mutual friends in the Los Angeles theater scene. The correspondent also complains about the rationing they are experiencing.
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: April 4, 1943.; Item no. 37; (6 p.; 7 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Friend Lois updates Estelle about goings on amongst friends and tells her about the war rationing going on. Lois hopes to see Estelle and Arthur back home soon.
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Wyoming., Date Created: June 1, 1943.; Item no. 38; (1 folded sheet (4 p.); 22 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Postcard, Los Angeles, Calif. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: June 10, 1943.; Item no. 39; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Letter, Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Mrs. Douglas Spears, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: October 1, 1943.; Item no. 40; (1 p. plus 1 clipping; 15 x 11 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Letter written on Heart Mountain letterhead. Estelle congratulates Lois on her marriage which she learned about from Lew Brown who sent Estelle a newspaper clipping (included).
      - Letter (copy), Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Mrs. Douglas Spears, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: October 5, 1943.; Item no. 41; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Copy of a letter from the Assistant Project Director, Heart Mountain Relocation Center. In light of Mrs. Spears's (nee Lois Hunt) request that Estelle refrain from contacting her, Anderson requests that Mrs. Spears please return a photograph belonging to Mrs. Ishigo care of this office.
      - Letter, Washington D.C. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: June 1, 1944.; Item no. 42; (2 p.; 21 x 16 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Helen Chapin encourages Estelle to remain hopeful about the possibility of relocation. Helen asks what type of work Mr. Ishigo does so that perhaps she can help find him a job.
      - Letter, Washington, D.C. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: July 12, 1944.; Item no. 43; (2 p.; 21 x 16 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Letter from Helen Chapin trying to cheer Estelle up. Helen tells Estelle about an artist friend in Pasadena that she should contact if she returns to California.
      - Letter, Burbank, Calif. to Mr. Schlosser., Date Created: November 28, 1945.; Item no. 44; (2 p.; 20 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Letter from Estelle Ishigo in which she complains about life in the Federal Public Housing Authority resettlement trailer camp in Burbank. She also writes about having difficulty finding employment.
      - Letter, Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Mr. Charlie Burn, Paramount Studio, Hollywood, Calif., Date Created: January 12, 1945.; Item no. 45; (2 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Letter from Arthur Ishigo seeking employment upon returning to Los Angeles from Heart Mtn. He is asking to return to the position he held prior to being relocated.
    - Letters and postcards Arthur and Estelle Ishigo received from their Japanese friends in the relocation camp., 1942-1945.; (62 items) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Pasadena, Calif. to Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., October 2, 1945.; Item no. 1 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Pasadena, Calif. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., 1945-10-22.; Item no. 2 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, McGehee, Ark. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., 1943-12-22.; Item no. 3 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Cambridge, Mass. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mtn., Wyoming., Date Created: January 7, 1945.; Item no. 4; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter from a friend of Estelle's studying at Harvard University. The correspondence mentions that a museum in Boston has "locked up" most of its Japanese art collection since the war.
      - Letter, Arcadia, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Wyoming., 1942-09-03.; Item no. 5 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Camp Santa Anita, Arcadia, Calif. to Art Ishigo, Pomona Assembly Center, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: May 27, 1942.; Item no. 6; (2 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Camp Santa Anita, Arcadia, Calif. to Art and Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: August 1942(?).; Item no. 7; (2 p.; 26 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Eddie writes that the "Hollywood gang" is at Camp Santa Anita. He advises the Ishigos on what to take with them to Camp and to store the rest with friends and not in a storage warehouse.
      - Letter, Camp Santa Anita, Arcadia, Calif. to Art Ishigo., n.d.; Item no. 8; (1 p.; 26 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Cambridge, Mass. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: December 18, 1944.; Item no. 9; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Yoshiaki writes Estelle that she has moved to Cambridge and has a job teaching Japanese language at Harvard. She asks Estelle how everyone at the Camp is taking the news of the lifting of West Coast evacuation and wonders if many of them will return to California.
      - Letter, Santa Anita, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: August 4, 1942.; Item no. 10; (2 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten casual correspondence from a friend of Estelle and Arthur Ishigo.
      - Letter, McGehee, Ark. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: October 13, 1942.; Item no. 11; (2 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter from a close friend of the Ishigos. The correspondent details his evacuation and his living conditions in an Arkansas Japanese American Relocation Center.
      - Letter, McGehee, Ark. to Arthur and Estelle., Date Created: December 29, 1942.; Item no. 12; (2 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter from a close friend of the Ishigos. The correspondent details his experiences living in a Japanese Relocation Center in Arkansas. He mentions that there is a ban on cameras and that evacuees are not allowed to leave the premises without a permit.
      - Letter, Mount Clemens, Michigan to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: July 12, 1943.; Item no. 13; (2 p.; 25 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter from a friend of Estelle and Arthur Ishigo. The correspondent is living in Michigan, working in a rose greenhouse.
      - Letter, Mount Clemens, Mich. to Mr. and Mrs. A. Ishigo., Date Created: January 17, 1944.; Item no. 14; (2 p.; 26 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter from a mutual friend of Estelle and Arthur Ishigo. The correspondent writes about his employment in a rose greenhouse in Michigan and searching for employment.
      - Letter, Montebello, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. E. Ishigo, Burbank, Calif., Date Created: December 20, 1945.; Item no. 15; (2 p.; 21 x 13 cm. plus 1 card; 13 x 20 cm. folded to 13 x 10 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        This is a handwritten letter and Christmas card. The correspondent writes about moving from a Japanese Relocation camp in Lomita, Calif. to a house in Montebello, Calif.
      - Letter, Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: June 10, 1944.; Item no. 16; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter written on behalf of the U.S.O. Family Club in appreciation of Estelle Ishigo's performance.
      - Letter, Heart Mtn., Wyo. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: June 17, 1944.; Item no. 17; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter written on behalf of the U.S.O. Family Club.
      - Letter, Denver, Colo. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 29, 1945.; Item no. 18; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        "Form" letter from a friend describing his life in Denver, Colorado.
      - Letter, Denver, Colo. to Estelle., Date Created: December 17, 1945.; Item no. 19; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter accompanying a check. The correspondent is an employee of the U.S. War Relocation Authority.
      - Letter, Manzanar, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: January 4, 1944.; Item no. 20; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm. plus 1 p.; 26 x 18 cm.); (Text in Japanese) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Manzanar, Calif. to Mr. Shick Ishigo., Date Created: March 12, 1944.; Item no. 21; (4 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter from a friend of Arthur Ishigo's who was also relocated to Pomona Relocation Center and then again to Manzanar Relocation Center.
      - Letter, Kirkland, Ill. to Mrs. E. Ishigo, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: October 19, 1944.; Item no. 22; (1 p.; 24 x 16 cm.); (Text in Japanese) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Ann Arbor, Mich. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mt. Wyoming., Date Created: May 26, 1945.; Item no. 23; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter from an acquaintance of Mrs. Ishigo. The correspondent writes of teaching Japanese at the University of Chicago and the University of Michigan.
      - Letter, Veradale, Washington to Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: July 10, 1945.; Item no. 24; (1 p.; 27 x 19 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter from a former Heart Mtn. resident asking for copies of sheet music to Japanese songs Estelle performed with the Heart Mountain band.
      - Letter, to Mrs. Ishigo., Date Created: August 15, 1945.; Item no. 25; (1 p.; 22 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Chicago, Ill. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: August 29, 1945.; Item no. 26; (2 p.; 23 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Frances writes Estelle that she is very much enjoying civilian life away from the Camp. She is visiting her sister in Chicago but will be returning soon to California and hopes Estelle will as well.
      - Letter, Fort Riley, KS to Mr. Ishigo, Heart Mt. Relo. Center, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: September 17, 1942.; Item no. 28; (2 p.; 27 x 17 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter from a Private in the armed forces who is awaiting a call to duty. He is a former resident of Heart Mountain.
      - Postcard, Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: April 14, 1943.; Item no. 29; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Signature on card illegible; correspondent is a Camp administrator. Informs Estelle that they will need more pictures for the Quarterly Report.
      - Postcard, Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: March 17, 1943.; Item no. 30; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Signature on card illegible. A Camp administrator notifies Estelle that a book she expected has arrived and will be held for her.
      - Postcard, Times Building, Los Angeles, Calif., n.d.; Item no. 31; (1 illustrated postcard (col.); 10 x 14 cm.); (Text in Japanese script. Card not postmarked.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Postcard, Butte, Mont. to Mr. and Mrs. Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: October 31, 1945.; Item no. 32; (1 illustrated postcard (col.); 10 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        A note from the Ands(?) family thanking the Ishigos for their kindness while the family was at Heart Mountain.
      - Postcard, Caldwell, Idaho to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 5, 1945.; Item no. 33; (1 illustrated postcard (col.); 10 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card to Arthur and Estelle Ishigo., Item no. 34; (1 sheet (col.) folded twice; folded to 12 x 9 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        A card from the Nakashimas who were at the Granada Relocation Center in southeastern Colorado. It was also known as "Amache Camp"
      - Postcard, St. Paul, Minn. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: February 2, 1943.; Item no. 35; (1 illustrated postcard (col.); 10 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Mr. Iwanaka, now at Hamline University, writes Estelle that "free" life in St. Paul is very good.
      - Postcard, Tule lake, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: June 17, 1944.; Item no. 36; (1 illustrated postcard (col.); 10 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        A brief note to the Ishigos to let them know that he had arrived at the Tule Lake Relocation Center.
      - Postcard, Arcadia, Calif. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: June 27, 1942.; Item no. 37; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Card from a Japanese American draftee who is also an aspiring artist.
      - Postcard, to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Pomona Assembly Center, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: August 17, 1942.; Item no. 38; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        A friend writes from a train en route to camp in Wyoming.
      - Postcard, Newell, Calif. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 5, 1943.; Item no. 39; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Mr. Torigoe writes Estelle that he has settled in at Tule Lake and thanks her for everything she did for him while he was at Heart Mountain.
      - Christmas card to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo., Item no. 40; (1 sheet (col.) folded twice; folded to 15 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card to the Ishigos., n.d.; Item no. 41; (1 sheet (col.) folded twice; folded to 14 x 17 cm.); (Signed: Masa, Bette and Sharon) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card to the Ishigos., n.d.; Item no. 42; (1 sheet (col.) folded twice; folded to 14 x 17 cm.); (Signed "Eddie") (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card to Arthur Ishigo., n.d.; Item no. 43; (1 sheet (col.) folded twice; folded to 14 x 11 cm.); (Signed "Murozaki") (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card, Heart Mountain, Wyo. to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: December 21, 1943.; Item no. 44; (1 sheet (col.) folded twice; 15 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Card from fellow internee.
      - Christmas card, Evanston, Ill. to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mtn., Wyoming., Date Created: December 8, 1943.; Item no. 45; (1 card; col. ill.; 14 x 30 cm. folded to 14 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card., n.d.; Item no. 46; (1 card: col. ill.; 13 x 20 cm. folded to 13 x 10 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card, Hollywood, Calif. to Mr. Ishigo, Heart Mtn., Wyoming., Date Created: December 26. 1944.; Item no. 47; (1 card: col. ill.; 13 x 20 cm. folded to 13 x 10 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo., Item no. 48; (1 card: col. ill.; 15 x 22 cm. folded to 15 x 11 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card, to Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: December 14, 1944.; Item no. 50; (1 card; col. ill.; 14 x 30 cm. folded to 14 x 15 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter from a friend of Estelle's reporting that he will begin teaching at Harvard University.
      - Christmas card, Heart Mtn., Wyo. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: December 21, 1943.; Item no. 51; (1 card; 24 x 32 cm. folded to 24 x 16 cm. (col. ill.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handmade card with a linocut print on the cover. Handwritten on front, "H.M. Xmas - '43; We threw a spaghetti feed to celebrate the birth of Jesus."
      - Postcard, La Crescenta, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Art Ishigo., Date Created: December 22, 1942.; Item no. 53; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.); (Handpainted postcard (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Postcard, Hillcrest Sanitarium, La Crescenta, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: October 2, 1942.; Item no. 54; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Postcard, Hillcrest Sanitarium, La Crescenta, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: December 14, 1944.; Item no. 55; (1 postcard; col. ill.; 9 x 14 cm.); (Handmade greeting card (linocut)) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mountain Relocation Center, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: December 21, 1944.; Item no. 56; (24 p.; 21 x 13 cm. plus 1 card: col. ill.; 10 x 10 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten letter addressed to Estelle Ishigo from a friend living in the Ishigos' previous Los Angeles neighborhood. The letter is very detailed and contains personal information regarding the correspondent's marriage, divorce, and family life.
      - Letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: June 9, 1942.; Item no. 57; (1 p.; 27 x 17 cm. folded to 17 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - New Year greetings., n.d.; Item no. 58; (1 card: col. ill.; 15 x 24 cm. folded to 15 x 12 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card., n.d.; Item no. 59; (1 card: col. ill.; 10 x 13 cm.); (Handprinted Christmas card) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card to Estelle Ishigo., n.d.; Item no. 60; (1 card: col. ill.; 15 x 24 cm. folded to 15 x 12 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Postcard, Pasadena, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mtn., Wyoming., Date Created: September 27, 1945.; Item no. 61; (1 postcard; 9 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Handwritten postcard containing a poem.
      - Letter, to Mr. and Mrs. Ishigo., 1942-07-31.; Item no. 62 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Christmas card, Hillcrest Sanitarium, La Crescenta, Calif. to Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mtn., Wyoming., Date Created: December 21, 1943.; Item no. 63; (1 card; 14 x 22 cm. folded to 14 x 11 cm.); (Handmade linocut print. Note written on back of card) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Letter, La Crescenta, Calif. to Estelle., Date Created: August 13, 1942.; Item no. 64; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 4)
        Letter head = "URAII Cosmetics, 1124 So. Normandie Ave. Los Angeles, Calif." Correspondent is a friend of Estelle's and a fellow artist. She writes about being in Hillcrest Sanitarium with "tubaculars." She complains about bad food and people dying.
    - Incidental correspondence of Estelle Ishigo relating to her internment in the relocation camp., 1942-1945.; (7 items) (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Letter, Los Angeles to Estelle Ishigo, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: June 8, 1942.; Item no. 1; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Signed by Helen H. Burkness, Agent. Letter from the Div. of Industrial Welfare stating they have collected back wages due Estelle Ishigo from Heller Drug Store.
      - Letter, Los Angeles to Estelle Ishigo, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: June 11, 1942.; Item no. 2; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letter addressed to Estelle enclosed with a check for back wages from Heller Drug Store.
      - Letter, Los Angeles to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: July 10, 1942.; Item no. 3; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letter enclosed with a check "representing adjustment of your wage for work performed at Heller Drug Co.," signed Helen H. Burkness.
      - Letter, Chicago, Ill. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: September 29, 1943.; Item no. 4; (1 p.; 14 x 28 cm. plus 1 card; 7 x 10 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letterhead = World Philosophy, formerly the Occult Digest, the Maha Publishing Co., Chicago, IL. Letter written by the editor of "World Philosophy" thanking Estelle for a watercolor she received.
      - Letter, Cambridge 38, Massachusetts, to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: September 12, 1945.; Item no. 5; (1 p.; 21 x 14 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letterhead: Harvard University Press. Letter to Estelle Ishigo stating they have no openings for illustrators.
      - Letter, West Springfield, Mass. to Miss Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: October 16, 1944.; Item no. 6; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letter signed Strathmore Paper Co. Advertising Dept. Letter in response to a request for a sample book of Strathmore Artist papers and Boards.
      - Letter, Billings, MT. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: February 23, 1945.; Item no. 7; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letter re. an order Estelle placed for carbon pencils.
      - Letter, Hollywood, Calif. to Arthur Ishigo, Heart Mtn., Wyoming., Date Created: August 4, 1943.; Item no. 8; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 5)
        Letter accompanying a check for $103.50, the remainder of money left in Arthur Ishigo's Paramount Pictures credit union savings account.
    - Correspondence exchanged between Estelle Ishigo and Alan Eaton, Russel Sage Foundation, on the compilation of Beauty Behind Barbed Wire., 1945-1948.; (39 items) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 1, 1945.; Item no. 1; (4 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letterhead: Russell Sage Foundation-Dept. of Arts and Social Work, Allen Eaton, Department Director. Enclosed is a copy of a letter to Mr. Mechau (Director of Reports, War Relocation Authority) from Allen Eaton.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 2, 1945.; Item no. 2; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)